你在被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监视你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我知道  因为它是我造的
I know because...I built it.
我设计这台机器是
I designed the machine
为了侦测恐怖行动  但它却看到了一切
to detect acts of terror, but it sees everything--
与普通人相关的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people.
像你一样的普通人
People like you.
而政府认为这些罪行无关紧要
Crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner.
一个有能力介入其中的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为被当局追捕
Hunted by the authorities,
我们只能秘密行事
We work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
不管你是被害人和行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
如果你的号码被列出来
if your number's up,
我们就会找到你
we'll find you.
疑犯追踪 第1季 第4集
字幕翻译：YYeTs人人影视
我一闭上眼睛  就能看到他
Every time I close my eyes, I see him.
他不放过我
He won't stop.
也许我已经死了
Maybe I'm already dead.
三号病房  在走廊尽头  左手边第二扇门
Surgical three--down that hall, second door on the left.
好
Yes, all right.
谢谢
Thank you.
八号房的戴维森先生需要全血细胞计数
Mr. Davidson in eight needs a CBC,
做心电图和便携式胸透
An EKG, and a portable chest x-ray.
五号房的孩子需要缝针
And the kid in five needs stitches--
头部撕裂  伤口四厘米
4-centimeter head laceration.
那四号房的那个呢
Uh, what about the guy in four?
他已经等了三小时了
He's, uh, been waiting for three hours.
谢谢
Thank you.
你今天很忙啊  我本来不想来的
You look rather busy today. I was hoping to avoid this.
不好意思让你等这么久
Oh, sorry about the wait.
-我是提尔曼医生  -你好
- I'm dr. Tillman. - How do you do?
你好
Hi.
看来你是背痛
I see that you are experiencing some back pain.
我的医生去开曼群岛打高尔夫了
My doctor's playing golf in the Caymans.
我只需要再拿点止痛药
I just need a refill on my pain medication.
好吧  程度1―5  你的背有多痛
All right, on a scale of one to five, how bad's your pain?
好的情况下是3  今天可不是好情况
On a good day, three. Today is not a good day.
抓着我的手
Squeeze my hands.
好吧
All right.
从你的骨骼结构来看
Judging from your bone grafts,
看你做过脊椎融合手术...
It looks like you had spinal-fusion surgery about...
-一两年前吗  -是的
- A year or two ago? - Yeah.
如果你长期背痛
You know, if your pain's chronic,
还有其他治疗方法
There are other treatments.
你怎么受的伤
How were you injured?
说来话长了
It's a long story.
拜托  你能不能就给我开一下...
Please, I was hoping you might be able to just...
处方药
Give me a prescription.
你真的应该全面检查一下
You really should have a full workup.
做下CT  核磁共振
C.T., mri...
但你是我这周来接待过的最有礼貌的病人
But you are the most polite patient I've seen all week,
那我就破例一下吧
so, I'll make a exception.
好吧  这是三天的药
Okay, this is for three days.
如果你还是痛  一定要回来看医生  好吗
If you're still in pain, you have to come back, okay?
很好  提尔曼医生
That's quite all right, dr. Tillman.
我就需要这些
I have everything I need.
该去工作了
Duty calls.
-保重  -谢谢
- Take care. - Thanks.
机器又跳出一个号码吗
Machine spit out a new number?
梅根・提尔曼
Megan Tillman--
以第一名的成绩毕业于哥伦比亚医学院
Graduated Columbia medical school top of her class,
从开始做住院医生起就没请过一天假
Hasn't missed a day of work since her residency began.
道格  我去吃点东西
Hey, Doug, I'm gonna go grab some lunch.
有什么事就呼我
Page if you need me.
她一周在医院要呆上80个小时
She puts in 80 hours a week at the hospital--
单身  独居
Single, lives alone.
你好  请给我汉堡和薯条
Hi. Burger and fries, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
-不好意思  -没关系
- Oh, sorry. - Not at all.
医院有什么人和这个医生有过节吗
Anybody at the hospital have a problem with the doctor?
没有被投诉过  也没有治疗不当的诉讼
No complaints, no malpractice lawsuits--
友善  受欢迎
Seems friendly, well-liked.
这么说我们完全不知道机器为什么吐了她的号
So we've got no idea why the machine singled her out.
来嘛  和我们去喝一杯
Come on, grab a drink with us.
就算是工作狂晚上也要放松啊
Even workaholics need a night off.
工作狂也要休息
Workaholics need rest.
我要回家睡觉了
I'm going home and hitting the hay.
-好吧  -也就是说...
- Okay. - In other words...
也就是说  我们得一直盯着她
In other words, we'll have to watch her
查出她到底被卷进了什么麻烦事
around the clock to figure out what kind of trouble she's in.
里瑟先生  如果你要加薪
If you'd like a raise, mr. Reese,
只管跟我开口就好
all you have to do is ask.
医生是早上六点的班吧
Doctor has a 6:00 a.m. Shift, right?
是的  怎么
Yes, why?
看来她改变主意要出门了
Looks like she's changed her mind about going out.
你这样的女人不该一个人坐在这
Girl like you shouldn't be sitting here all alone.
你这样的男人不该毛手毛脚
Guy like you should watch where he puts his hands.
-慢着  芬奇  -别这样
- Hold on, Finch. - Come on.
我看到有个人拿着枪
I got a guy with a gun.
美女
Hey! Baby!
老天  求你
Oh, god! God, please, please!
别打我脸  求你了
Not my face, please! Please.
没事吧
Everything all right?
-出什么事情了  -我去解了个小手
- What happened? - had to make a pit stop.
慢着
Wait.
华尔街仔
Mr. Wall street...
我今天是第二次看到这人
Second time I've seen this guy today.
你肯定
You sure?
绝对  他今天早上在餐车旁边撞了提尔曼一下
Yeah, he bumped into Tillman at the food truck.
你去试着报答一下看看
See if I can repay the favor.
-借过  哥们  -看着点啊  哥们
- Dude, sorry. - Watch it, man.
此人名叫安德鲁・本顿
Guy's name is Andrew Benton.
他随身带苯二氮平类药物
He's carrying benzodiazepine...
氟地西泮
Roofies...
迷奸用药
Date rape drug.
我想我找到威胁了  芬奇
I think we just found the threat, Finch.
我们不是唯一在跟踪提尔曼医生的人
We're not the only ones following Dr. Tillman.
医生大约在三点半左右独自离开了夜店
Doctor left the club alone around 3:30.
她在天亮前就到了医院
She showed up at the hospital before sunrise,
门诊了一个崴了脚的  一个心脏病发作的
Treated a twisted ankle, a heart attack,
还有一个手被割伤的
And a cut on a hand.
中间没停过
She hasn't stopped once,
就喝了杯咖啡
Except to get herself a cup of coffee.
-她一心扑在工作上  -不只是工作
- She's dedicated. - and not just to her job.
我问过酒保
I asked the bartender.
她这周几乎每晚都在这个夜店里泡着
She's been at the club almost every night of the week.
双重生活
A double life?
很危险啊
A dangerous one.
她引来了不必要的关注
She's attracted some unwanted attention.
全名叫安德鲁・威廉・本顿
Full name is Andrew William Benton.
他是供职于哈德逊自由金融的一个投资银行家
He's an investment banker at Hudson Liberty Financial.
本顿有前科吗
Does Benton have a record?
理论上说  没有
Technically, no,
但针对他有一长串的指控
But there are a string of accusations against him--
尾行  骚扰  性侵害
Stalking, harassment, sexual assault.
尽管目前为止  他从未被正式起诉过
As far as I can tell, he's never been formally charged.
这哥们很像是性侵罪犯
Guy fits the profile of a sexual predator,
我认为他挑了提尔曼作为下一个猎物
And I think he's picked out Tillman as his next victim.
我进去了
I'm in.
有什么不寻常的地方么
Anything out of the ordinary?
这人喜欢给自己领地画记号
Guy likes to mark his own territory.
不做咖啡
No coffeemaker.
本顿喜欢更强力的东西
Benton's into something stronger.
刚到手他的电邮  个人档案
Just got his email, personal files.
很快就知道他还干过什么
We'll see what else this guy's into.
那是什么
What is that--
中央街劫案的监控录像
Uh, surveillance from the Center Street Robbery?
你那个前中情局的人吗  他也有份
Your ex-CIA guy-- is he in it?
人气主演
He's the star.
这个带滑雪面罩的吗  你怎么就知道是他
The guy in the ski mask? How do you know it's him?
我就是知道
I just do.
但你看看这个
But look at this.
-看到没  -看到了
- See that? - Yeah.
-他们接头了  -接头
- They had an exchange. - Exchange?
看好
Watch.
就这
Right there.
他跟那个小个子说了什么
He says something to the little guy.
再看  小个子答复了点什么  就这
And look, little guy says something back, right there.
你知道他叫什么  住哪儿吗
Well, did you get his name, his address?
有  他是马登利纳的一个律师助理
Yeah, he's a paralegal from Marmostein Ribner.
名叫伯戴特
Name's burdett.
你觉得这个伯戴特听到了点东西
You think this Burdett heard something?
没准就能帮你找到那人
Might lead you to your guy.
这些女人都是谁
Who are these women?
本顿的猎物
Benton's conquests?
-梅根・提尔曼在里面吗的吗  -没有
- Any of them Megan Tillman? - No.
他还没上网查她
He hasn't researched her online.
他甚至还没有查她公寓周围
He hasn't even looked up the area of her apartment
或者是医院周围
Or the hospital.
他跟医生之间的没有任何关联
There's nothing to connect him to our doctor.
他很谨慎
He's careful...
花样百出
Methodical.
也许他不是总那么小心
Maybe he wasn't always so careful.
我过滤了一遍他的履历
I've been combing through his history.
本顿先生有一个已经被撤销的大学旧记录
Mr. Benton has an old college record that's been expunged.
也许有助于帮我们了解这个人
Might illuminate what kind of a man we're dealing with.
但  我们要权限
But-- - we need access,
而我刚好认识个能帮忙的人
And I know someone who can help.
我对你跟弗斯科警探之间
I'm not all that comfortable
的协议并不是很放心
With your arrangement with detective fusco.
他很有用
He's an asset.
他是个想谋杀你的腐败警察
He's a corrupt police officer that tried to murder you.
他不是第一个要杀我的人
He's not the first person who's tried to kill me.
弗斯科会是个好同志
Fusco will stay in line.
你的警探宠物现在是很乖  里瑟先生
Your detective is a nice pet to keep, Mr. Reese,
但是早晚
But sooner or later...
会反咬你一口
He'll bite you back.
怎么回事  你连你老爹都跟不上了
What's the matter? You can't keep up with your old man, huh?
我去捡
I got it.
请问下  是弗斯科警探么
Excuse me, Detective Fusco?
你们几个是干什么的
Who are you guys supposed to be?
我们几个是干贩毒的
We're supposed to be drug dealers,
出了一帮蠢的要死的死条子
Except a group of very foolish cops
偷走了我们的货
Stole most of our product.
我不懂了
You got me confused.
你们得去找斯蒂尔斯警探
Detective Stills is the guy you want.
斯蒂尔斯失踪了
Stills is missing,
而其余你的那些黑条子兄弟都吃了官司蹲了号
And the rest of your dirty cop friends are in jail.
只剩下你了
That leaves you
这批货是市值一百万的可卡因
On the hook for a million dollars worth of cocaine.
我们要追回我们的货款
We want our money.
那我去柜员机上直接给你们取现提款好了
Let me go to the A.T.M., make a withdrawal.
爸  还扯啥呢  我们再来玩啊
Dad, come on, let's play.
马上来  小子
Just a minute, buddy.
我们的下一代  他们
Our children-- They, uh...
看到太多暴力了
They see too much violence.
你脖子上带着一颗好头颅
You have a good head on your shoulders.
两天之内给我们送钱过去  这样你还能顶着脑袋
Bring us the money in two days, and you get to come home
回家看孩子
To your son with it still attached.
双赢
Win-win.
医生已经在吧台蹲了一个晚上了
Doctor has been parked at the bar all night.
目前为止  不见本顿
So far, no sign of Benton.
她白天在医院干16个小时
She puts in 16-hour days at the hospital,
晚上出来瞎混
Stays out all night.
为什么
Why?
是什么在驱使她
What's driving her?
芬奇  你等下
Uh, Finch, hold on a second.
主角终于登场了
Man of the hour just showed up.
一杯马蒂尼  满上
Just a martini, up.
日子漫长  工作劳神  好容易撑到下班
Long day, stressful job, finally off the clock,
就只想一个人清净
And you just want some peace,
但总有那么一些不知趣的蠢材跑来打搅你
But some clueless idiot keeps brothering you.
吧台前的独身女子么  你还能指望些什么
Girl alone at a bar-- what do you expect?
我不是在说你
Oh, I wasn't talking about you.
如果你还没注意到
In case you haven't noticed,
我正拿着棍子抽他们呢
I'm beating them off with a stick here.
是吗
Is that so?
什么都好  就是千万别给我上酒
Whatever you do, do not offer to buy me another drink.
我叫凯特
Well, I'm Kate.
安德鲁
Andrew.
很高兴认识你
It's nice to meet you.
为什么她要用假名
Why is she using a false name?
我刚好要去外面透透气
Well, I was just about to go get some fresh air.
这么巧  我能跟你一起么
Yeah, you know what? Do you mind if I join you?
-你要去哪  -不知道
- Where are you headed? - I don't know.
你常逛夜店  你来说
You're the club guy. You tell me.
凌晨三点  市里多半都打烊了
3:00 A.M., town's pretty much closing down.
我倒是知道个地方  就在这个转角附近
I do know a place right around the corner--
齐全的酒吧  床很舒服
Full bar, comfy bed.
你家啊
Oh, your place.
你想不想去我家
Oh, do you want to go to my place?
当然行
Sure.
来嘛  你想干什么都成
Come on, we'll do whatever you want.
出去玩  喝两杯
We'll hang out, have some drinks--
或者弄点更嗨的
Maybe something stronger.
我明早还有早班
I have to work early in the morning,
下次吧
But maybe next time.
你知道上哪找我
You know where to find me.
疑犯追踪 第1季 第4集
字幕翻译：YYeTs人人影视
等等
Wait a minute.
她在干嘛
What's she doing?
我还不知道  但是她肯定另有打算
I'm not sure, but she's up to something.
芬奇
Finch...
不是本顿在尾行医生
Benton's not stalking the doctor.
是医生在尾行他
She's stalking him.
是我
It's me.
我知道已经晚了
I know it's late.
这是我的错  我现在懂了
It was my fault. I know that now.
我想要忘记这一切  但我做不到
I tried to put it out of my head, but I can't.
表紧张  莱奈尔
Easy there, Lionel.
上回你拿枪指着我
Last time you pointed a gun at me,
就没好果子吃对不对  你还来
It didn't end in your favor, now, did it?
是你不该神出鬼没
You shouldn't sneak up like that,
斗牛帮毒贩最近盯上我了
With the thugs from the Toreros Cartel after me.
锡那罗亚州的那个斗牛帮吗
Toreros from Sinaloa?
我在墨西哥呆过
I spent a little time in Mexico.
那你该知道他们是个行刑队
You know that they're a death squad.
跟他们对上  人头落地
You cross them, and your head winds up in a bag.
但你已经跟他们对上了
But you've already crossed them.
安德鲁・本顿被注销的犯罪记录  你倒是有没有
Andrew Benton's expunged record--do you have it?
我还附送了你点彩头  法医报告也在里面
Even an added bonus-- I got the M.E. Report.
漂亮
Wonderful.
我给你做的够多了
I do a lot of things for you.
你还想让我继续干的话  你就得保护我
You want me to keep doing them, you got to protect me.
你得把那些人做掉
You got to take these guys out.
就是说我现在要给你打工了
So I'm working for you now?
不然我就没法帮你了
It's either them or me.
纽约的腐败警察多了去了  莱奈尔
Lots of crooked cops in this town, Lionel.
找个像你一样能干活的警察
It's not gonna be hard to find another one
还不简单吗
Just as useful as you...
还没那么多负担
With less baggage.
请给我报告
The report, please.
我已经很客气了
I did say "Please."
这才对嘛
That's the spirit.
芬奇  我知道为什么医生在尾行本顿了
Finch, I know why the doctor's stalking Benton.
96年时候  本顿是纽约大学四年级生
In '96, when Benton was a senior at N.Y.U.,
他性侵了一个才入学的新生女孩子
He sexually assaulted a freshman girl
就在一个兄弟会晚会上
At a fraternity rush party.
她的口供中说她想要取悦本顿
Uh, she said in her statement that she wanted to impress him.
毕竟他备受瞩目  还是明星运动员
He--he was popular, a star athlete.
于是她就跟他喝了点啤酒
So she had a couple beers with him,
她说他在酒里下了药
Claimed he slipped something in her drink.
那他为什么没被拘捕
Why wasn't he arrested?
她等了两天才报的案
She waited two days to report the assault.
估计是又羞又怕
Probably ashamed, scared.
毒物检验报告显示正常  强奸罪名不成立
Tox reports came back clean. Rape kit was inconclusive.
她放弃了指控
She dropped the charges.
那女孩子是谁
Who was the girl?
加百列・提尔曼  医生的姐姐
Gabrielle Tillman, the doctor's sister.
事情发生一年后  加百列被送进了急诊室
A year after the attack, Gabrielle was rushed to the E.R.
结果送到时候已经没救了
And pronounced D.O.A.
死因是服用抗焦虑药物
From an overdose of antidepressants
和安眠药过量
And sleeping pills.
这可不是什么偶然过量
This isn't an accidental overdose.
这是
This is--
她自杀了
She committed suicide.
所以机器给出了提尔曼的号码
And that's why the machine gave us Tillman's number.
她要杀了本顿
She's going to murder Benton.
那个害死她姐姐的男人
The man responsible for her sister's death.
正解
Correct.
芬奇  她是个悬壶济世的医生
Finch, she's a doctor who saves lives.
她如何能懂杀人是怎么回事情
She doesn't know what it's like to take one.
这会毁了她
It'll destroy her.
伯戴特先生  我是卡特警探
Mr. Burdett? Detective carter.
我之前跟你通过电话  关于那宗您目击的劫案
I called regarding the robbery you witnessed.
我能进去么
Uh, can I come in?
我在等你来
I've been expecting you.
不好意思有点乱
Sorry about the mess.
律师助理是吧
Paralegal, right?
在证物保管处查案子
At lockup looking into a case?
遗嘱认证法庭无法使
Probate court failed to require
执行人出示一份高保债券
A fidelity bond of the executor.
执行人所做的
The executor, in his turn,
则是把奥曼房产刨了个精光
Robbed the Ulman Estate blind.
-请坐  -谢谢
- Please sit. - Oh, thank you.
你是在此次劫案当中受的伤么
Were you injured during the robbery?
别担心  我不会起诉市政府的
Don't worry. I'm not gonna sue the city.
是旧伤了
This is an old injury,
尽管这事也没给我什么好处
Although the stress of the situation did not help.
我们在竭尽所能抓捕犯人
We're doing everything in our power to catch these guys.
伯戴特先生  介不介意我再请你回顾下当时的情况
Mr. Burdett, do you mind walking me through what happened?
我就在保管处的前台站着
I was standing at the counter at lockup.
然后他们就冲进来了  他们有枪
They came storming in. They had guns.
他们高喊要我们趴下贴地  于是
They were shouting at us to get down on the floor, so...
我照办了
I did.
抢劫过程中
During the robbery,
你有没有听到有人说  以利亚  这个名字
Did you hear any of the men say the name "Elias"?
应该没有  谁是以利亚
I don't believe so. Who's Elias?
你有没有看到他们的长相
Did you get a look at any of their faces?
没
No.
他们当中有没有人跟你说话
Did any of the men talk to you?
我不记得有
Not that I recall.
可是在我看来
Because it looks to me...
这个人跟你讲了些话
Like this man said something to you.
我还希望我别再被问一次这个事情
Oh, I was hoping I wouldn't have to go
没完没了的
Through all of this again.
是
Yes.
他跟我说叫我别再盯着他看
He told me to stop staring at him.
有意思
That's interesting.
大多数人的反应都是转开视线
Most people's instinct is to look away.
倒是从来没人说我跟大多数人一样
Well, I've never been accused of being like most people.
他还有跟你说了些什么吗
Did he say anything else to you?
没
No.
你有没有用各种方式与他交流过
Did you try to communicate with him in any other way?
此话怎讲
How do you mean?
当他抓着你的外套拎着你的时候
When he was holding you by your jacket.
我叫他放了我
I asked him to let me go.
你就说了那些话
And that's all you said?
卡特警探
Detective carter,
我想你应该是习惯于枪口下来去了
I suppose you're used to being around guns,
我想暴力犯罪的场景对你来说并不陌生
I suppose scenes of violence are commonplace for you,
但是我能向你保证  与我而言  十分恐怖
But I can assure you that for me, it was terrifying.
我当时怕极了  连眼珠子都不会转了
I was so terrified, I couldn't even look away.
所以  当他把我抓起来的时候
So, when he picked me up,
我以为我是死定了
I thought surely I was about to die.
所以  是  我是跟他沟通了
So, yes, I was communicating with him.
我是求他放过我
I was begging for my life.
很抱歉当时我具体说了什么话记不起来了
I'm sorry I can't remember the exact words I used.
那
Well...
如果你还能再想起来些什么  请给我电话
If you can think of anything else, please give me a call.
向你保证  我们一定会抓住他们
I promise you, we will catch this guy.
提尔曼在哪  里瑟先生
Where's Tillman, Mr. Reese?
她在上班
She's working.
而我正在处理我的副业
I'm taking care of a little side project.
怎么心神不宁的啊  哈罗德
What's got you worried, Harold?
卡特警探
Detective Carter.
我跟她见面谈了下抢劫的事情
I met with her about the robbery.
我必须得摸摸她的底
I had to know what she knows.
她很有干劲
She's motivated.
按某人话说叫  执着
Some might say "Fixated."
很快她就能追查到你身上了
It won't be long before she catches up to you.
还是早做打算为妙
Gonna have to have a plan when she does.
交给我去解决
I'm taking care of it.
我正在结交一位新朋友
I'm making a new friend on the police force.
他会帮忙解决卡特与弗斯科问题
He's going to help us with our problem with Carter and Fusco.
提尔曼20分钟后下班
Tillman's off in 20 minutes.
撤了
Got to go.
从酒吧出来  我们就去了他家
After the bar, we went back to his place.
他在我的饮料里掺了东西
He slipped something in my drink.
我就昏迷了
I blacked out.
当我
When I...
醒来的时候  我趴在他床上  全裸
Woke up, I was in his bed, facedown, naked.
我找不到我的衣服
I couldn't find my dress.
我想喊
I wanted to scream,
叫警察
To call the cops,
或者别的任何人
Someone, anyone,
但是我害怕
But I was afraid.
我哭着走了
I was crying when I left.
他只是笑着  还说我真是够狂野
He just smiled and said I was a real wild woman,
还说我们上班时再见
And he would see me at work.
现在每天我看到他  他脸上都是同一个笑容
Now every day I see him, and he smiles that same smile,
我就很想吐
And I want to throw up.
可我需要这份工  我不能辞职
I need this job. I can't quit.
这种事我也说不出口
I never talk at these things either.
-请问你说什么  -对不起
- Excuse me? - Oh, I'm sorry.
我只是自言自语
I didn't mean to interrupt. I...
我只是来弄点咖啡
Just wanted some coffee.
不好意思
Sorry.
没事  我今天是第三杯了
Son't be. It's my third cup today.
我一直以来参加这种活动  想让自己好受点
You know, I keep coming to these things, hoping I'll feel better,
但是只会让我更难受
But they only make me feel worse.
这咖啡真难喝
This coffee's terrible.
里面那个女人  你认识她吗
Uh, that woman in there-- y-you know her?
不
No.
只是  我认识像她那样的人
But, uh, I know someone like her.
你呢
What about you? - hmm?
你为什么来这
Why are you here?
我失去了一个很亲近的人
I lost someone very close to me.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我无时无刻不在回想
Not a day goes by I don't think
我当时能做什么好挽回这一切
About what I could've done.
是啊
Yeah.
很多年后我才明白我朋友到底出了什么事
It took me years to piece together what happened to my friend.
我说  我觉得我能
You know, I thought I could...
挺过去
Live with it.
我终究放下了
I put it behind me.
我有份好工作
I had a good job,
美好人生
A good life.
然后我在一个月前看到了他
And then I saw him a month ago.
于是一切又都回来了
And it all came back.
他那时在吃晚饭
He was eating dinner
就在我家附近的一间法国小餐馆
At this little french place in my neighborhood.
他在约会
He was out on a date.
他看起来相当志得意满
He looked content.
我的世界支离破碎  而他却志得意满
My world is shattered, and he looks content.
抱歉
Sorry.
我不知道怎么就和你说起这些来了
I don't know why I'm telling you all this.
人总得找个人聊聊
Hey, everybody needs someone to talk to.
我叫约翰
I'm John.
我叫凯特  凯特・莱曼
I'm Kate. Kate Leman.
这些照片是那个变态的奖杯吗
The photos are some kind of sick trophies of his victims.
说服了这些女人跟他一起吸毒
Benton convinces these women to do coke with him,
偷偷对她们用镇定剂  然后再强奸
Slips them a sedative, then rapes them.
到了早上  她们就怕地不敢再出面
In the morning, they're too afraid to come forward
而且还把自己搭进去了
And implicate themselves.
我想这就能解释为什么
I suppose that explains
这些针对他的指控一直都主动撤销了
Why the charges against him are consistently dropped.
这人够堕落
The guy's depraved...
最喜欢侵犯和羞辱这些女人
Gets off on violating and humiliating all these women.
他不会罢手  芬奇
He's not gonna stop, finch.
那医生给我的假名你查到什么有用的吗
Did you get a hit on that name the doctor gave me?
我找到三个凯特・莱曼
We got three hits on Kate Leman--
就是她给本顿的那个假名
The same pseudonym she gave to Benton.
第一个是住在布隆克斯的80岁老太太
The first is an 80-year-old woman living in the Bronx.
第二个住在上城区
The second is living upstate
女子劳教所
At a woman's corrections facility.
第三个有个邮箱
The third has a P.O. Box
就开在离提尔曼工作的医院一条街的地方
A block from Tillman's hospital.
她最近租了一辆面包车
She recently signed rental agreements for a van
和蒙特卡的一个度假屋
And a vacation home in Montauk.
你找到那房子了吗
You find the house?
还有些别的东西
And then some.
医生有用来彻底抹杀掉本顿的东西
Doctor has everything she needs to erase Benton for good.
你说的抹杀是什么意思
What do you mean "Erase?"
八磅碱  加热到300华氏度
8 pounds of lye, heated to 300 degrees--
尸体三个小时便无影无踪
Body will dissolve in three hours,
大约这个数
Give or take.
我就不问你是怎么知道的了
I will refrain from asking how you know that.
芬奇  她做事极为细致
Oh, Finch, she's meticulous--
策划所有这一切都是为了报仇
Planned everything to a "T,"
并且她会逍遥法外
And she's gonna get away with it.
我都忍不住要这么想
I'm beginning to wonder
她这么做是不是帮了这个世界一个忙
If maybe she's not doing the world a favor.
但提尔曼不是个杀手
But Tillman isn't a killer.
她要是这么做了  会毁了她的一生
She goes through with it, it'll ruin her life.
你有什么建议  里瑟先生
What do you suggest, mr. Reese?
我们不给她机会下手
We don't give her the chance.
我会想办法让本顿消失
I'm gonna find a way to make Benton disappear.
决定帮我了吗
Decided to help me?
我还是难以替代的哈
I'm not so easy to replace, huh?
我警告你  这些毒贩会从背后偷袭你
I'm warning you, these Cartel guys will put two in your back,
所以别给他们还手的机会
So don't leave any of them standing.
你要不要我...你真的不要我
You need me here-- you sure you don't want me
到后面去守着出口吗
to go around back and cover the exits?
不用  你在这就好
No, you're good right here.
警探
Detective?
钱拿来了吗
You got our money?
奥拉尔  圭埃尔
Orale, Guey.
你应该杀了他们
You're supposed to take them out.
你做什么  你偷他们的货吗
Hey, what are you doing? You stealing from them?
如果这能安慰你下  这是为了做好事
If it makes you feel better, it's for a good cause.
先生  麻烦一下
Sir, pardon me.
有什么问题
What's the problem?
没问题
No problem.
先生  你能听到吗
Sir, can you hear me?
我和你说  这一周真是太劲爆了
I'm telling you, this has been the craziest week.
我请你们喝酒
Drinks are on me.
他被放了
He's being released.
为什么
Why?
看那家伙  他有四个律师
Look at the guy. He's got four lawyers.
每个人身上的西装
Each of them got a suit on
比我半年的工资还贵
that costs more than I make in six months--
这种律师对法律的每个漏洞都一清二楚
The kind of lawyers that know every loophole
可以让像本顿这样的败类逃脱制裁
a piece of garbage like Benton can crawl through.
斗牛帮怎么办
What about the Toreros?
现在他们不仅要找我  还要找他们的货
They're gonna come looking for me and their coke.
那最好别让他们找到你  莱奈尔
Well, we better make sure they don't find you, Lionel.
你知道你给我惹了什么麻烦吗
You know what kind of hole you got me into?
我到底是在犹豫什么啊  干嘛不直接
What's stopping me right now from making some noise,
把你供出去得了
getting you arrested?
不知道哎  你在犹豫什么咧
I don't know. What's stopping you?
是我
It's me.
我知道已经晚了
I know it's late.
这是我的错
It was my fault.
我现在懂了
I know that now.
我想要忘记这一切  但我做不到
I tried to put it out of my head, but I can't.
对不起  小梅
I'm sorry, Meg.
我不是个好姐姐
I should've been a better sister.
求你
Please...
忘了我的电话
Just forget I called.
忘了这一切
Forget all this.
里瑟  提尔曼医生有动作了
Reese, dr. Tillman's on the move.
她不是在值班吗
I thought she was in the middle of a shift.
之前是
She was.
但她去休息了  还告诉护士
She went to take a nap and told the nurse
不要叫醒她
not to wake her.
现在她离开医院了
Now she's moving away from the hospital.
交给我
I'm on it.
不管你要做什么  要尽快
Whatever you do, do it quick.
她朝本顿的家里去了
She's headed toward Benton's loft.
好吧  明白
All right, got it.
伙计们  你们能晚点再来吗  我有点忙...
Can we do this later, fellas? I'm a little bus--
搞什么
What the hell?
里瑟  医生在本顿家已经有五分钟了
Reese, the doctor's been at Benton's loft for five minutes.
你到底死哪去了
Where the hell are you?
再见到你真好  莱奈尔
Nice to see you again, Lionel.
弗斯科警探欠我们一笔帐
Detective Fusco owes us a debt...
所以他拿了点东西来还债
So he made a little down payment--
就是你
You.
这算双赢
It's a win-win.
我们的毒品呢
Where's our cocaine?
我知道你
I know you.
那你肯定也知道要是招惹了斗牛帮
Then you know if you cross the Torero Cartel,
你就得准备掉脑袋
You lose your head.
真抱歉
I'm sorry.
现在道歉太晚了  伙计
It's too late to apologize, amigo.
不  我抱歉
No, I'm sorry...
是因为要掉脑袋的人是你
But you're gonna lose your head...
要是你老大发现
你一直在和你们的对头海湾帮卖命
杀了你老大的手下
还有他儿子
这是真的吗
Is this true?
闭嘴
Shut up.
那他怎么知道米盖尔的事
How does he know about Miguel?
闭嘴  他在说谎
Shut up. He's lying.
要是让我再看到你
你就准备掉脑袋吧
听着  这不是针对你  好吗
Look, it was nothing personal, all right?
我也没办法  他们要杀了我
I had no choice. They were gonna kill me.
我说了  你不是纽约唯一的腐败条子
I told you, you're not the only dirty cop in town.
我帮了你的忙
I called in a favor.
现在该换换了
It's time for a change of scenery.
你得替我做点其他事
You're gonna be doing something else for me.
还有  莱奈尔
And, Lionel...
下不为例
Don't do this again.
警官
Officer.
-请给我加二十块二号油  -当然
- Uh, $20 on 2, please. - Sure.
谢谢
Thanks.
我就猜是你
I thought that was you.
还记得我吗
Remember me?
你是互助小组的那个人
Oh! The guy from the support group.
好吧
Yeah.
我得走了
Well, I got to go.
让我请你喝杯咖啡吧  梅根
Let me buy you a cup of coffee, Megan.
得了  我知道这感觉很糟
Come on, I hear it's terrible.
你车里的那个被绑着的男人可以等等
The guy you got tied up in the back of the van can wait.
你很聪明
You're smart.
你也一直很小心
And you've been careful.
你应该不会被抓到
You probably wouldn't get caught.
但事实是  你永远也摆脱不了这件事
But the truth is, you'll never really get away with it.
你知道他是什么人
Do you know who he is...
他都做了什么吗
What he's done?
我知道所有安德鲁・本顿的事
I know all about Andrew Benton.
还有你  梅根
I know all about you, Megan.
我知道你是个很棒的医生
I know you're a damn good doctor.
我知道你的一生
I know that you've spent years of your life
都在治病救人
healing people.
我也知道如果你这么做了
And I know if you do this...
如果你冷血地杀死了那个男人
If you murder this man in cold blood...
你就会被吞噬
It will kill you.
你说你失去了重要的人
You told me that you lost someone.
这是真的吗
Was that true?
那你怎么能就这么让我袖手旁观
How can you sit there and tell me not to do something
你也知道你内心告诉你该怎么做吧
You know in your heart you would do, too?
因为我和你不同
Because unlike you...
我知道当你夺走别人的生命时
I know what happens when you take a life.
你自己生命的一部分也失去了
You lose a part of yourself...
不是所有的部分
Not everything...
只是最重要的部分
Just the part that matters the most.
你就是这样的吗
Is that what happened to you?
你不用非得这么做
You don't have to do this.
你现在还可以回头
You can turn around right now.
他看到我了  他看到了我的样子
He's seen me. He's seen my face.
我想我能和他聊聊
Well, suppose I have a little talk with him.
相信我  这不要紧
Trust me, it won't matter.
把你的车钥匙给我  梅根
Give me the keys to your van, Megan.
他做了这么多事
Everything he's done,
我只要把钥匙给你就行了吗
and I'm supposed to just hand you over the keys?
他就这么逍遥法外
He gets to walk free?
我又有什么
What do I get?
你能有第二次机会
You get a second chance.
你可以忘记过去
You get to let go.
重新回到你的生活
You get your life back.
那加百列又有什么
What does Gabrielle get?
她有对你的美好回忆
She gets to keep her memory of you.
我不明白
I don't get it.
你是谁  你为什么要来
Who are you? Why are you here?
我告诉过你了
I already told you.
每个人总得找个人聊聊
Everybody needs someone to talk to.
谢谢
Thank you.
里瑟
Reese?
提尔曼医生在哪
Where's dr. Tillman?
她没事
She's fine.
我开着她的车
I have her van...
本顿也在
And Benton.
你准备怎么做
What are you gonna do with him?
我会和他聊聊
We're gonna have a little talk.
你为什么这么做  芬奇
Why do you do it, Finch--
这个机器  这些号码  所有这些事
The machine, the numbers, all of it?
我说过了  里瑟先生
I told you, mr. Reese...
我有我的理由
I have my reasons.
我们和卡特警探的小问题怎么解决
And our little problem with detective Carter?
已经解决了
Taken care of.
警探
Detective.
队长  我很荣幸...
Captain, it's a real pleasure--
省省吧
Save it.
有人叫我把你调到这来  还不要问理由
I was told to assign you to this desk and not ask questions.
所以我不问为什么
So this is me not asking questions.
那你也打电话给你的朋友
And this is you calling your friend
让他处理掉他拍的我的照片
And telling him to lose the photos he's got of me.
但要是你搞砸了
But if you mess up,
我可不会在意你背后有什么人
I really don't care who's watching out for you.
我会亲自把你踢出去
I will personally see that your ass fries.
祝你愉快  警探
Have a great day, detective.
-孩子很可爱  -谢了
- Cute kid. - Thanks.
那是什么  中心街的保管处劫案吗
What's that--the center street lockup robbery?
那可是件大案子
That was something.
-有线索吗  -有一点
- Any leads? -A few.
-你刚调过来吗  -是的
- You just transfer? - Yeah.
弗斯科警探
Detective Fusco.
我是卡特
Carter.
看来你以后要和我一起合作了
Looks like you're stuck with me.
我在哪
Where am I?
我家里有个女人...她
That woman in my loft-- she...
她把我电晕了
Tased me.
别担心  我让她走了
Don't worry. I told her to leave.
她不是做这种事的人
She isn't cut out for this.
她是救人的人
She fixes people...
不像我们
Not like us.
我们是毁了他们的人
We break them.
我不懂  你是谁
I don't understand. Um, who are you?
你要把我怎么样
What are you gonna do to me?
说实话  我还没决定
Honestly, I haven't decided yet.
我问你个问题
Let me ask you a question.
你觉得人真的会改变吗
Do you think people ever really change?
我是说  你伤害无辜的人
I mean, you-- you hurt innocent people,
而我
And I-- well...
很久以来  我就负责杀你这种人
For a long time, I killed people like you.
求你了  我不是你想的那种人
Please, I'm not who you think I am.
你搞错了
This is a mistake.
等等  好吧
Wait--wait, o-o-okay.
我是做过一些事
I've done some things. Um...
一些越轨的事
I've crossed some lines.
但我不会再做了
But I won't do it again.
我发誓
I-I swear.
求你了
Please...
放我走
Let me go.
我可以放你走
I could let you go,
因为你要知道  你之后的日子
'cause you know for the rest of your life
我都会监视着你
That I'd be watching you.
如果你再敢伤害任何人
And if you hurt anybody...
我会阻止你
I'd stop you.
也许你可以改变
Maybe you could change.
也许我也可以
And maybe so could I.
但事实是
But the truth is...
人们的本性难移是吧
People don't really change, do they?
不  他们可以改变
No, they, uh-- they can.
我可以
I can.
而你...
And, um, you--
我
I--
我觉得你不会杀我
I don't think that you're going to kill me.
-是吗  -是的  因为...
- No? - No, because...
我能看到你内心...
I can see, inside, that you're a--
是个好人
A good person.
你是个好人
You're a good man.
好人
Good?
很早以前  我已经失去好的部分了
I lost that part of myself a long time ago.
我不知道我还能不能重新找回来
I'm not sure if I can find it.
这对我来说还重不重要
I'm not sure it matters anymore.
也许这样更好
Maybe it's better this way.
也许我就该去做好人做不了的事
Maybe it's up to me to do what the good people can't.
也许这世上已经没有好人了
Or maybe there are no good people.
也许这才是唯一正确的决定
Maybe there are only good decisions.
求你了
Please...
你...
You--
别做出你会后悔的事情
Y-you don't want to do something that you're gonna regret.
你觉得什么会让我更后悔
Which do you think I'll regret more--
是放了你
Letting you live
还是杀了你
Or letting you die?
安德鲁
Andrew...
帮我做出正确的决定吧
Help me make a good decision.